One of the very first things that China
would do in a conflict, they would jam
GPS.
Jam everything. Jam everything, right?
And so if your weapon systems, if your
drones are unable to operate without
GPS,
you're not in a good spot. And again,
what I have talked to a lot of military
leaders and leaders in the E Y and the L
Y about is everybody's going to tell you
they can do it, right? But just ask them
to say what's your qualitative data from
Ukraine, what's your quantitative data?
Walk us through how you are achieving
this. If they can't show you like
[music] I can pull up 20 different
missions from Ukraine that we've done in
the like the past couple months. In
every single one of those, GPS
communications is jammed. Go to Ukraine
and ask the Ukrainians what products
work when GPS is jammed.
And I promise you they'll say well the
like the only one that works
when GPS is jammed at like [music] and
it's not connected to a fiber optic
cable, they're going to say Shield AI.
Hey, hello. That was a good
Hi Brandon. Our show has been following
defense tech for a long time and the
Shield AI is a company we have been
watching closely and I'm really glad to
have you here today. Can you give our
audience a quick introduction of
yourself?
>> Yeah, absolutely. One, thanks for having
me Fox. Really excited to to be here
speaking with you today.
A little introduction on myself. Let's
see.
So one, my name is Brandon Tseng. I'm
the president and co-founder of Shield
AI. Prior to founding Shield AI, I was a
Navy SEAL. I deployed twice to
Afghanistan, once to the Pacific Theater
before I
started my career in the Navy as an
engineering officer on board a ship and
I deployed to the Arabian Gulf on a
ship. I'm a mechanical engineer from the
US Naval Academy. I've got three kids,
girl, boy, girl, 5 years old, 3 years
old, 4 months old.
Live with my wife and my kids in
Virginia in the United States. And my
fun facts are I am a Taiwanese American.
My dad was born in Taipei
and my grandfather served in the
Taiwanese government as a foreign
service diplomat
from 1949 to I think like 1983
>> Wow.
>> in South America.
So couldn't be more excited to
be speaking with you and you know,
really excited to share all the great
stuff that we're doing here in Taiwan.
Yes. Okay. Also, as you mentioned, you
spent 7 years in Navy SEALs. Yep. What
experience made you like decide to leave
the military and found a company? Yeah,
look, I was um
I really loved my time in the SEAL
teams. It was a lot of fun. We got to do
a lot of really cool missions.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, yeah, it was awesome.
Um
jumping out of airplanes shooting guns
is it's a it's a really great time.
But at that stage in my career, I had
already been a Navy SEAL platoon
commander.
I didn't have a dream to run a Navy SEAL
team, which you know, a lot of my
friends now 20 years in are now at that
stage of life.
And I just wanted to try something else.
I was very attracted to
you know, the the tech entrepreneurs of
the world, the Elon Musks, the Jeff
Bezos.
And so I actually remember the reason
one of the things like why I started
Shield AI, Elon Musk said in his
interviews in like 2011, 2012, he wanted
to work on the problems that would most
impact humanity.
It was the internet and so that's why he
started PayPal and x.com.
It was space travel for SpaceX and
sustainable energy, which was Tesla and
SolarCity.
And I remember thinking to myself like
what is [snorts] a big problem that
humanity faces that Elon Musk is not
working on.
>> [laughter]
>> And you know, what I decided was you
know, what the problem of warfare has
plagued humanity for 4,000 plus years.
It is one of the most destructive forces
on the planet. It destroys lives. It
destroys livelihoods.
And I thought you know, I have this
unique set of experiences. I could
contribute to helping solve this problem
of of warfare. And I could work on that
for a long time and just to be clear,
it's not I don't think it gets solved in
my generation or even my kids. But I in
the same way Elon Musk wants to become
multi-planetary. I think the idea of a
world without war is
is a mission that is worth working
towards. And so that's why I started
Shield AI. Was there a specific moment
that you thought like something need to
be fixed?
Honestly, there wasn't a specific
moment. It was um
it was actually like so many different
experiences. And so when I was in the
SEAL teams, it's not like I would go on
a mission and be like oh man, if I had
just had
an AI piloted quadcopter, I could have
done so this so much better and so much
safer. Like when I was a SEAL, I had all
the best technology in the world. I felt
very well equipped
to do what I could do. Now
when I was thinking about Shield AI, it
was basically saying okay, let me take a
step back. Like what can I work on? I
want to do something with AI and
autonomy. I wanted to do something in
the military.
Right, wanted to do something
entrepreneurial. And it was more about
not what I had not the experiences, but
well I mean the experiences played into
it, but asking myself what is the what
should the military of 2035 look like?
What is the role that AI and autonomy
plays
and how can I help contribute to that
world, right? And this was back in 2015.
So I was asking myself what the military
20 years later should look like.
military operations be conducted and
decided that basically everything should
be powered, maneuvered, commanded by
artificial intelligence.
>> Yeah. Oh, so you founded a company with
your brother. So how is like building a
company together with Your brother?
>> [laughter]
>> How do you think it is?
Do you guys have siblings? No, I I
don't. So I can't imagine that.
[laughter]
We we can see lots of founders in
Taiwan.
>> [clears throat]
>> They started a company with their their
spouse maybe.
>> Yeah, man, that could be [laughter] bad.
I'll tell you the only thing harder than
starting a company with a your family
member like your brother or your sister
would be doing a company with your you
with your spouse.
No, look, it's been I'm really thankful
that I got to start a company with my
brother.
The pros of doing a company with a
family member. Like you have incredible
trust
in them. You communicate so clearly
with them and so quickly with them.
There's no sugarcoating anything. It's
just like right, it's your brother.
You're like I've known he's known me my
entire I've known him
>> [laughter]
>> his entire life. He's known me for all
but 2 years of his life, right?
When I didn't exist. But
and so that's the pro of it. The con of
it is that you communicate so well and
so clearly and quickly with each other
that you really know how to bother each
other. And so
look, he
him and I what's good is
we have like a Venn diagram. We have
some overlapping skill sets and
overlapping values, right? We we have
the same values.
But skill sets
like he believes in leadership a lot of
the same way that I do. So that's good,
right?
Certain things around communication, he
believes in the same way that I do.
He's an engineer like a hardcore
engineer and his brain works very
differently than my brain. And I'm I'm
an engineer also, but and like I know
how things work, but again, just very
very different. And so sometimes when
we're working on a problem and he he you
know, his solution versus my solution,
I'm like how the hell do you see it in
that way? Like what are you are we
looking [laughter] at the exact same
thing? But that actually is super
helpful in business to have you know, a
lot of different perspectives on how to
do things. So it's been it's been great.
You know, we're working on it.
>> [laughter]
>> There'll be some complaints, right? If
I'm honest, but like what we were were
there you know, and if he he wants to he
maybe he'll watch this.
>> [laughter]
>> But it's been it's been fun in a lot of
ways. And look, there've been times
where we're yelling at each other. We're
fighting with each other.
And those are the hard times, but we've
been able to recover, right? Again,
probably because of that that trust,
those values at the end of the end of
the day. You know, shout out to him.
Probably because of that love also. So
but sometimes it makes it hard for you
know, hard for me to love him in some
instances when we're fighting. So
So majorly, who is the face to face the
investors?
So
I I do so well, for a long time
like Ryan was the CEO for 10 plus years.
We brought on a new CEO
and Ryan's still at the company. He's
still He's a president, I'm a president
of the company.
Obviously, we just want to see the
company win.
So, we both would do fundraising very
outwardly facing. He'd be doing the
meetings, but I
I would be the driving force of all the
fundraising. And so, that's like just my
core role and responsibility. I'd bring
Ryan in for you know, the investor
meetings as needed, but you know,
there's the pitch and then there are is
20 different diligence calls that you
follow up with the investors on. And so,
him and I would both be part of the
pitch, but then I would be doing these
20 follow-up calls with investors to
make sure they're they're comfortable
understanding the risks, understanding
the opportunities. That's what I would
be doing. Still do to this day. Got it.
I was I was I was doing investor calls
this morning.
Yeah.
At 1:30 in the morning here.
>> [laughter]
>> Because it was 1:30 in the afternoon
there. 1:30 and 5:00 p.m. was doing
investor calls.
Um back in 2015, AI was not the
mainstream.
People thought it was just for cats.
Cat pictures.
Yeah, indeed [laughter] at the time.
Is military background is a plus or
minus when raising money in in that
time?
Um
So, my military background, like what
I'm forever thankful for is I have like
just the mentality of I'm going to
accomplish the mission. That is super
important. And
I you know, all the values that I
learned in the SEAL teams that have been
ingrained with me, that's super
important when running a business.
But in 2015, no one was investing in in
the military, right? In Sorry, in
defense technology did not exist in
2015. Yeah, it was blank. 100%.
I'll share a funny story. So, Peter
Levine, who is an investor of ours,
legendary investor from Andreessen
Horowitz, he's on our board of
directors. He's a good friend of mine.
He's been on the Midas list, which is
the top investors in the world for like
God, 15 plus years. Just a really long
time. Um he's also a professor at
Stanford University at their business
school. And so, [clears throat] in 2017,
Andreessen Horowitz had just invested in
Shield AI
and Peter came out to Harvard Business
School where I was at the time.
And he gave a lecture on investing.
And I didn't have an opportunity to go
to the lecture, but a lot of my friends
went to the lecture.
And I asked I called my friends up. I
said, "Hey, what did Peter talk about?"
And they said, "Oh, well, Peter says he
just invests in really dumb ideas and he
just invested in the dumbest idea yet,
which was Shield AI."
And so, [laughter] I you know, I laughed
and I was like, "All right, I'll have to
ask him about it." So, I called Peter
up. I said, "Peter,
how's it going?" He's like, I said, "I
heard you just you told everybody at
Harvard that you just invest in dumb
ideas and that you just invested in the
dumbest idea yet, which is Shield AI."
And he said, "Yeah, I did say that."
But he's like, "Look, it's a really dumb
idea right to get into a car with your
stranger, right? My mom growing up,
they're like, don't don't ever get into
a car with a stranger, right?" He's
like, "That's Uber, right?" He's like,
"It's a really dumb idea to stay at a
stranger's house, right? You're never
supposed to go into a stranger's house."
He's like, "Your dumb idea is everybody
knows a dumb idea to work
work with the military, do government
contracts. It's so slow. It's you know,
they
the only people that play in that space
are Lockheed and Raytheon and Northrop.
Like it doesn't make any sense to do
technology in the military.
He's like He's like, "Now, he's like,
time will tell if that was a dumb idea
or a clever idea.
And like your job, Brandon, is to go
show the world that it was a clever
idea."
He's like, "But it could end up being
dumb. We just don't know yet." And so,
you know, the cool thing is right now in
2026,
I think with defense tech as an asset
class in of itself and and certainly
Shield AI played a role in that. SpaceX,
Palantir, Anduril, I think those four
companies have created were the trail
like in in great credit to SpaceX and
Palantir first and foremost.
But then, you know, if they were the you
know, very much Shield AI and Anduril
being the next ones to create this asset
class.
Um So, before we talk about the
products, can you explain in simple
terms what is Hivemind and how is it
different from something like
self-driving cars?
Okay. So, there are two aspects of
Hivemind that I'm going to make it
really simple.
There is the pilot, the AI pilot, which
goes on top of any
drone. It can be a drone as small as a
quadcopter. It can be a drone as big as
a fighter jet or as big as a ship or a
submarine.
Because people sometimes think it's it's
you know, there's lots of different
types of drones out there.
And it is self-driving technology for
unmanned systems, right?
It's no different than what Tesla is
doing or Waymo is doing. We just are
applying the same technical approaches
that those companies are and applying it
to military platforms.
And what it enables like it an AI pilot
perceives its world with its sensors.
It thinks about its world with its GPU.
And then it
it maneuvers in the world, right? With
its you know, its engines, its controls,
its wings, whatever it is. It's
maneuvering.
It's an autonomous system. You and I are
autonomous system. We use our senses to
perceive the world. We think about the
world with our brain and then we actuate
our muscles to engage and then we learn
from those experiences. That is the
exact same thing that Shield AI is doing
for drones, AI pilots for drones, for
military systems. It's the exact same
thing Tesla is doing for self-driving
cars and humanoid robots.
Um
And then the second part of Hivemind,
we offer
an enterprise software product. We call
it Hivemind Enterprise. It's a software
development kit. But the easiest way to
think about it is it's cloud code for AI
pilot development. It makes it really
easy. And so,
what I can confidently say is no company
in the world is faster at building AI
pilots and integrating them onto
unmanned systems
than Shield AI. And so, in Taiwan, I'll
just
talk about quickly here.
Um
And assist, our contract with Anduril is
about delivering Hivemind Enterprise,
the software development kit, so that
Anduril so that Taiwan companies, Taiwan
drone companies can quickly build AI
pilots and integrate them onto their own
drones, their own unmanned systems. So,
2 weeks ago, our team was out here. They
met with the top 10 drone companies
in Taiwan to basically say, "Hey, how
can we help you build an AI pilot for
your drone or help you help yourself
build an AI pilot so that they can
operate while GPS and communications are
jammed so that they can swarm, so they
can execute missions autonomously."
Sorry, that's long long answer.
Yep.
Yep. 100%. Okay. Also, you recently flew
Anduril's Fury with Hivemind. So, can
you tell us what happened and why it
matters? Yeah. So,
again, what we are doing with Hivemind
is building AI pilots for a number of
different unmanned systems and drones.
We have done probably 20 plus to this at
this time. We have done
everything from the V-Bat to
to quadcopters to a full-size helicopter
made by Airbus
to one-way attack drones to very large
jet-powered drones made by Kratos. And
we've done unmanned surface vessels and
we've done unmanned ground vehicles. And
we're actually working on AI come AI
astronauts for satellites.
Um and
so, for Anduril,
the cool thing that we were able to do,
Shield AI, there was a competition.
So, the collaborative combat aircraft
program, which is the US Air Force's
program to field
these things called CCAs. Collaborative
combat aircraft. It's a it's a AI
piloted fighter jet. There is the
hardware component and then there's the
software and AI pilot component. And so,
Anduril and General Atomics won the
first increment of the hardware
component. And Shield AI and RTX
won the first increment of the AI pilot
component. And so, what they did, they
said, "Okay, Shield AI, you're paired up
with Anduril. You're going to
your Hivemind is going to fly their Fury
drone.
And RTX, which is Raytheon, you're
paired up with General Atomics and your
AI pilot is going to fly General
Atomics.
But we can switch them out. Shield AI
can fly General Atomics' aircraft if if
we want to also."
And we've flown General Atomics' drones
also. So,
but that is you know, it was just it's a
really cool thing to do. What's really
cool is that that program in the US
military is the first major program that
has bifurcated into a hardware prime
contractor and a software prime
contractor. So, we're the software prime
contractor.
>> Oh. So, what is the loyal wingman? How
is different from a regular drone? Yeah,
so a loyal wingman,
um that's what the collaborative combat
this this first increment. They're meant
to fly ahead alongside
of F-35s, of F-22s,
uh carrying, you know, weapons, being
piloted by AI, and they're able to read
and react based on, you know, what the
F-35 is doing or, you know, what the the
air power is doing. That's the concept
of a loyal wingman. So, the other I will
say what we are we're building our X-Bat
fighter jet, and I can talk about that,
but that is actually
it can be a loyal wingman, but it's also
independent. It can do the the challenge
with the aircraft that are being built
right now, the other CCAs, they are
loyal wingmen. They're not meant as
independent aircraft that operate on
their own.
Um the X-Bat is meant to can operate,
you know, by itself. Oh. So, two
different AI system can switch on the
same
drone or aircraft. So, what does it
matter?
Um look, at at the end of the day, the
the military is looking to
they want more people to build AI they
AI pilots. They want more people to
build um hardware because they want to
keep it competitive. They want a
competitive marketplace. They don't want
the Joint Strike Fighter program, which
was, you know, 20 year It's an amazing
capability, but it was 20 years late.
They want They recognize that
competition is good to get the best
products into the ecosystem, into the
warfighter, uh get the best products to
the warfighter fastest, right? Um so,
they are going to always do these
increments. They're always going to have
um these AI pilot competitions, which I
think is good. Um
yeah, for the industry. Okay. Um so,
your drone can work with without GPS and
without communications. Uh what's the
hardest part about that? Oh man, it's
just hard.
Yeah, yeah. Oh, look, it's um I tell
self-driving technology is probably
about it's it's on the same technical
difficulty level as landing a rocket
from outer space.
>> Yeah.
Totally agree. So, and it's like
[clears throat] that's why it's like
it's taken Tesla
about 11 years to get to where we are
today. It's a really hard problem to
solve. And so, there are differences in
terms of self-driving cars in the
military in the sense that we have
different missions and operations, and
we're doing it on lots of different
platforms versus self-driving cars and
and self-driving cars have to worry
about a lot of other different things.
>> Yes. Um but it's just a hard hard
technology. Um which I I've lost a lot
of hair, a lot of years of my life
working on.
>> Okay. Um but yeah, perhaps like the
I don't think people realize like how
how hard it is. It's really easy to say,
but
>> There there are tons of edge cases.
Yeah. Especially in the the the the
special occasions.
>> Yeah, I'll tell you everybody says they
can do GPS jamming, and everybody has an
alternate position navigation timing
scenario.
Go to Ukraine and ask the Ukrainians
what products work when GPS is jammed.
Um and I promise you they'll say, "Well,
the like the only one that works
uh when uh GPS is jammed at like and
it's not connected to a fiber optic
cable, they're going to say Shield AI."
Wow.
>> Yeah. Okay. So, it was proven in
Ukrainian. Many times.
And and look, to the Taiwan audience
that's going to be listening to this and
why it's important,
the very first like thing one of the
very first things that China would do in
a conflict, they would jam GPS. Jam
everything. Jam everything, right?
Um and so, if your weapon systems, if
your drones are unable to operate
without GPS,
um you're not in a good spot. what I
have talked to a lot of military leaders
and leaders in the the EY and the LY
about is everybody's going to tell you
they can do it, right? Um
cuz there's a lot of snake oil salesmen
out here like in the military, but just
ask them to say, "What's your
qualitative data
from Ukraine? What's your quantitative
data? Walk us through how you are
achieving this?" And if they can't show
you like I can pull up 20 different
missions from Ukraine that we've done in
the like the past couple months. And
every single one of those, GPS and
communications is jammed. Yeah, we they
will jam your jam your weapons on from
space, from internet, and from
everywhere.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
So, another product getting a lot of
attention is X-Bat. Yeah.
>> And it's like on the t-shirt.
>> [laughter]
>> Wow.
Yeah, I'll I'll tell you about this.
So, can you please
>> can have I'll give this one to you guys.
introduce the X-Bat and where it
stand right now. Yeah. So, um X-Bat,
this thing,
>> [laughter]
>> this is I don't know, this might be
1/1000 the size of it.
Um is a vertical takeoff launch and land
fighter jet um that is AI piloted that
Shield AI is building. It is the first
AI piloted vertical takeoff launch land
fighter jet ever built. The problem that
it is meant to solve is um runways are
day zero targets. So, again, what what
what would China do on the very first
day of a conflict? The runway. They're
going to jam your GPS and
communications, then they're going to
blow out your runways. You know what the
United States does like when we go to
war? We jam the enemy, we jam the radar
[laughter] systems, and we blow up their
runways.
>> Yeah, I saw that in Iran. Yeah. Iran,
Venezuela, first thing we did, seven
Venezuela has They only had seven
fighter jets. What do we do? We blow up
their runways, blow up their seven
fighter jets on the runway.
India and Pakistan, right? When they're
fighting, what does India go after? They
go after the Pakistani runways. Uh
Israel and Iran, Iran has tried to blow
up Israel's F-35s that are sitting on
their runways. Russia-Ukraine, Ukraine
has targeted
uh Russian jets on their runways via
whether it's ATACMS missiles or whether
they stuck quadcopters into the country
uh and blew them up that way, but they
were targeting the runways.
Um and Russia has obviously blown up
Ukrainian runways. Um and so, it's a big
problem
um because especially for a country uh
like Taiwan where it's like look, a
small country, you're only having only
have so many runways. Yeah. And so, if
all of a sudden in the first day of your
conflict, your runways are destroyed,
and your air force doesn't have that
vertical takeoff launch land fighter jet
capability, you're you're stuck. You're
not in a good spot. So,
um we are building The other thing that
it does is it brings a lot of the
capabilities that you would find in an
exquisite fighter jet, a fifth
generation, a sixth generation fighter
jet um to uh a platform that is, you
know, the F-35 normally costs $100
million. It's an amazing aircraft, but
when you look at the There's the
platform, there's a $10 million pilot,
then there's the runways, the hardened
bunkers, the uh
the the maintenance, the operations all
in that capability. Again, it is
amazing, and like it's like very
thankful that the US has built it. I'm
very thankful that the US can afford it.
Um but uh
the total cost of that aircraft is
roughly about
two all in cost $200 million per
airplane.
Uh X-Bat is meant to deliver the exact
same like mission sets at $30 million
uh per airplane. Low low low cost. Yeah,
low cost. Um and so, that's what we're
building. Um I'll talk like I'm happy to
tell you like one other really cool
thing about it, but yeah, this is a a
small version. Takes off, then flies. Um
and the reason why this is on a stick,
when fighter pilots are going through
their mission debriefs,
uh they have little fighter jets
[laughter] on sticks and they're, you
know, flying them around showing things.
Not a fighter pilot, I've just seen how
fighter pilots do [laughter] it.
Yeah, I Top Gun. Yeah, yeah, yeah. So,
we now give all of our, you know, our
customers, you know, that we're working
with a little X-Bat on a stick so that
they can, you know, maneuver them.
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah.
>> But this is yours now, Fox.
>> [laughter]
>> Thank you.
So, I heard that you're planning to
first vertical takeoff this fall. Yeah.
Yeah, so we're going to do our first
vertical takeoff launch and land this
fall. The other cool things about X-Bat
like for your listeners, it's
it's um
if you you should YouTube the X-13
aircraft. So, a lot of people say, "Oh,
can you actually build a vertical
takeoff launch land fighter jet?" The US
Air Force built one in the 1950s. Uh the
engine technology wasn't good enough to
make it useful, but um
and it was really hard for a pilot to
actually land the aircraft,
>> Yeah. uh but it's all proven technology.
And so, with engine technology where it
is today, we can actually make it a
useful capability. And that is like a
lot of people say, "Okay, what's the
difference between an X-Bat?" Sorry to
take your gift back.
>> [laughter]
>> What's the difference between an X-Bat
and a
uh you know, a an Anduril Fury or a
Lockheed Vectis or a General Atomics
Gambit aircraft, right? These other CCAs
that are being built. It's like, yeah,
vertical takeoff launch and land is one
thing that's very different.
>> Yes. The other thing is uh the engine
that we are using. So, we are the only
you know, if you call this a
collaborative combat aircraft, we're the
only one using a military-grade fighter
jet engine. So, we use the same engine
that is in the F-15, the F-16. It's the
GE F110. And so, what that means is we
are able to generate eight times more
thrust than those other airplanes that I
just mentioned.
Um and with that thrust, you can do
vertical takeoff launch and land, you
can carry more payload, uh you can
uh fly at higher altitudes, um and then
you can actually run electronic uh
warfare electronic attack payloads uh at
much further distances um and do the
same missions that you know, an F-18
Growler would normally do. And that's
again, you know, very specific
electronic warfare uh aircraft. Um so,
um yeah, we carry more weapons, we fly
higher. Um and again, I people don't
realize how big this thing is. We're
basically
>> [sighs]
>> 70% the size of an F-18. We're a big
fighter jet. Um and like if you compare
it to the CCAs, um
they're actually like we might be twice
the size of something like uh
an Anduril Fury. Okay. We're much
bigger. Yeah. And as you mentioned, the
the Fury. So, X-Bat and the Anduril's
Fury, are they competitors or do they
work together? Or you you are making the
AI for
Anduril's drone. Yeah, yeah. Building
our our building your own craft is not a
common I I look at our competition for
X-Bat. Um we want to go after the
fighter jets. Mhm. Like right? These are
the you know, the F-16s,
uh the F-18s of the world, the the
Eurofighters.
Um we are going after
uh you know, the fourth, fifth, and
sixth generation fighter jets that are
being built. That's how I think about
the marketplace. You know, and look,
there's a world where these everything
from an X-Bat to uh these other CCAs
that are being built, they're going to
take market share from that. Yeah. Um we
designed X-Bat to, you know, in our
belief take as much market share as
possible. Well, as you mentioned before,
uh Shield AI is working with ANSYS in
Taiwan. Yep. Uh with the Hivemind into
local drones project. How did the
partnership start? Oh man.
So, we actually started with the Taiwan
Navy. Okay. Oh yeah. So, yeah, um
but by working with the Taiwan Navy on
V-Bat and Hivemind, um I think we were
able to connect with ANSYS and they
became very interested. So, so for the
Taiwan Navy, you know, our objective is
to provide 24 hours a day, 7 days a week
uh maritime domain awareness around all
of Taiwan. And if GPS or communications
are jammed, it doesn't matter um because
we have Hivemind on board. Um
And so, by working with the Navy, we got
connected with ANSYS because they were
very interested cuz Taiwan wants to
build, you know, I think start they're
going to start with 40,000 indigenous
drones that they build themselves. Um
again, we think like I don't think we
know we can help on the AI uh pilot side
of that and help in you know, build the
AI help Taiwan
build its own AI pilots, own those AI
pilots, and integrate them onto
Taiwanese drones.
So, why is Taiwan
uh as you mentioned before, they it
started with Taiwanese Navy? Yep. So,
why is uh why did you choose to
cooperate with Taiwan?
>> Taiwan? Yeah. Why come to Taiwan? You
have Japan, Korea Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Look, um so,
one we work with uh Japan. Japan Navy
has is where they we were selected for
their maritime self-defense uh program
for the V-Bat. Um we work with Korea. A
lot of Korean companies are using our
Hivemind Enterprise. Uh Korean Aerospace
Industries is is one of them. Um I and
and I tell I was uh
on a panel with uh director uh
AIT director Raymond Green uh the other
day at the Indo-Pacific Forum. And you
know, I thought it was important cuz you
know, I do come to Taiwan a lot now.
Uh I came six times last year. This is
my second time this year. I'll be here
probably eight times. I joke I'm
probably going to buy an apartment here.
>> [laughter]
>> Ah. Yeah, like I I actually love it
here. Okay. But like why am I in Taiwan?
Um
my mission
our mission is to protect Shield AI's
mission is to protect service members
and civilians with artificial
intelligence systems. Our mission is to
deter war. Um and so, when I think about
perhaps the largest problem that faces
the entire world as it relates to
national security and global stability,
it is the threat of China invading
Taiwan. And so, if Shield AI can help
Taiwan, if we can help the United States
deter a war, well,
that I think is like it's super
important. That's why I am here. I wish
that Shield AI was of the size and scale
and I wish that the technology was
further along back when Russia invaded
Ukraine. And if we had already
delivered, you know, 300 V-Bats to
Ukraine, I think and had put them up on
the border, I think you wouldn't have
seen Russia invade. I want to you know,
help Taiwan with all of their
capabilities so that China says, "You
know what? I'm never going to invade
Taiwan. It's just not worth doing it."
Um we're trying to buy peace, we're
trying to buy diplomacy uh another day.
So, that's why I spend a lot of time on
Taiwan. And it's like
it's [gasps]
>> [sighs]
>> I can't think of a more important place
to you know, to be if you care about
uh national security uh and and
deterrence. Inside, the last thing about
it is like
like the cool thing is we always get uh
our V-Bats are flying in Russia-Ukraine.
Our V-Bats are flying in the Caribbean
Sea going after all the drugs
uh with the US Navy and the the Coast
Guard. Um we get to operate whenever
there's a conflict. They're taking our
V-Bats over to
uh the Arabian Gulf for you know, uh
Iran. Um we were operating uh against
the Houthis in the Red Sea. Um
I actually What's better than like
V-Bats flying in combat is V-Bats
helping deter the the conflict in the
war, right? In in Hivemind and X-Bat,
that's I
like I think countries and what Taiwan's
doing really well, um they are investing
ahead of a conflict um
because they take it seriously.
So, coming back to Hivemind, uh
what are some new things that Taiwanese
drones can do once they're installed
Yeah, they'll be able to operate while
GPS and communications are jammed,
they'll be able to autonomously execute
missions, you can train them to execute
whatever mission you design for it. Uh
and then they will be able to swarm and
work together. So, it'll be really cool.
Okay. Uh so, another question is uh
China is moving very fast in AI and
drones. So, how do you see the
competition right now? And how long can
Yeah. US keep the lead? Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah. So, US is number one
with software um in AI. But it like I I
tell everybody, it's not it doesn't
matter if you're number one. Actually,
like being in first place is not a good
place to be because everybody is always
nipping at your heels and everybody
wants to chase you. Um and what is
frightening about China is their cycle
time, the amount like how quickly they
can innovate and go to the next like
they go from version
.1 to version 1.0 to version 2.0 to 3.0
4.0 5.0 faster than anybody in the
world. Um Yeah, I saw like trying to
clone the V-Bat. Yeah, yeah, they will.
Yeah,
>> [laughter]
>> again, they'll they will try to iterate
and copy and
uh they will again, that's what they
won't get it right the first time. But
it's like
what they can do is they can actually
start spitting out capability really
really again, quickly and iterating on
it very quickly, going to the second
version, third version, fourth version.
Um
And so, that's that's what I I worry
about. Um I do think what where they are
better than the USA, uh they're better
at manufacturing and production. Um the
US is not
bad at it, just to be clear. I think a
lot of times people say like, "Oh, the
US can't." It's like, no, we're actually
very good at manufacturing and
production also. Uh but China is better.
Um
but when I think about it's not about
China versus the USA, um
it like if I were to think about China
versus the USA, I actually kind of like
lose sleep. Uh it worries me. But when I
think about China versus the USA plus
Taiwan plus Japan plus Korea plus
Australia plus the Philippines plus
India plus the Middle East plus Europe,
that is when I'm like, you know what?
We're we're actually like we outproduce
China in terms of the uh the
manufacturing production. Our
innovation, our software capabilities
will be better than China. And I don't
see how China would ever be able to take
on the world. Right? When I say the rest
of the world that USA plus Taiwan,
Japan, Korea, all these countries that
work together and share
a similar way of life. That's what like
that's why I can actually sleep
peacefully. So. Great.
So. This is
uh uh
a racing issue recently.
And the topic was Yeah. uh recently list
as a national security risk
by the war department for refusing
fully autonomous weapons. Yep. uh and
the public
who said private company should not have
the kind of veto power. What's your
take? Yeah. Look, I
I obviously support the Department of
War 100%.
So, just want to be super clear on that.
What I what I tell people, and this is
what I think a lot of folks in the US
tech industry
and and probably other tech industries
throughout the world,
but certainly in the United States, what
they don't appreciate is how responsible
the USA is with incredible technology,
incredible power. The USA right our
military
has
lots of nuclear weapons. We have
aircraft carriers that can do the most
amazing things. We can do we have
all the power the military has so much
power in the world.
There's nothing like it on the face of
the planet the the US military.
And if you look the US military has
actually been an incredibly responsible
of that power. It's like the the
Spider-Man quote. I don't know if you
with great with great power comes great
responsibility. That is the USA. When I
was hunting terrorists in Afghanistan we
had our Predator drones. We had all this
all this technology
the sensors
where we could find terrorists in their
house.
The number of times we said hey, let's
actually not do a drone strike, right?
Because there we don't know who's in the
house alongside that we know the
terrorist is in the house, but does he
have a wife in the house? Are his kids
in the house?
What are the chances that like is it
does he live too close to someone who is
a non-combatant?
And we probably for every drone strike
that we did, I my guess is we probably
walked away like 15 drone strikes
because we were worried that someone
else would get hurt.
And so
again, it's just a lot of care and
responsibility goes with that power. And
that's what people you know everybody's
like they they get worried about the
military. It's like no no no the checks
and the balances and the care that they
have is why I feel like why I fully
support it. And I if you haven't seen
how that is done from the
[clears throat] inside, I understand
it's hard, but having been on the inside
of that power apparatus and seeing like
what we could do you're like okay we
again great power great responsibility
and
the US military is like that. Yeah. So
so you have been on the battlefield. So,
how do you think soldiers on the front
line would see this issue? What I'll
tell you is I think in World War II 90%
of soldiers
fought on the front line and 10% were in
support logistics role, right? Um
Fast forward to the war in Afghanistan
where I was
and it was 10% of soldiers were on the
front line and 90%
were in support, right? It was much
smaller
people doing it. As AI and drones become
more prevalent more ubiquitous on the
battlefield, I think you will see front
line soldiers the number of front line
soldiers go down. I do think you'll
start to see drone versus drone
much more. It already exists Yeah. in
in Ukraine where you'll see like
actually I'll tell you we've had FPV
drones try to hunt down the V-BAT. Now
we just fly too high for them to get to
and it's they've been unsuccessful. But
that's drone versus drone and look you
have a FPV pilot trying to hunt down an
autonomous drone, but you're going to
see more just like AI piloted drones
trying to take out other drones. And so
which is look I think it's a good thing.
It means less people getting killed on
the battlefield. That's the end of the
day.
So, I think Elon Musk has a quote like
whoever has you know the smartest drones
ends up winning in conflict and and
that's what I think will actually
happen. So
So, it sounds like good things.
I think it'll be a good thing.
I think you'll find it
Look, even technology
war is very destructive, but because of
you know advances in technology over the
past 20 years it's become more precise
at least for the USA, right? We're very
very precise.
And
that is you know it will
AI will just help it make it even more
precise more lethal,
but very surgical versus you know having
to to destroy an entire city. Okay.
So, does Hivemind have any red line that
you have drawn? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Sorry.
Yeah. Like for me
I
I hold the belief that the moral
decision to use lethal force to take a
human life, which I have had to make as
a Navy SEAL,
should only belong to human beings. That
is my policy. That's Shield AI policy.
That's the US military's policy. That's
NATO's policy. At the end of the day
there's going to be a human that says
okay yes you can take that life or no
you can't take that life and they'll set
the parameters
via the rules of engagement. So,
that's what you know
I
I can't envision a like no one wants
autonomous killer killing machines.
And so we don't we are not going to do
that.
Okay. So, it will always come back to
humans to make the big decisions.
For yeah for the moral decisions. Yeah.
Yeah. Big decision to take another human
life.
Human in the loop. Yeah. Uh last
questions. There are many young
engineers in Taiwan who are very
interested in defense technology. But
they didn't know how to start with.
Any advice you will give them?
Um one would love to hire them at Shield
AI. So, we're growing here in
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah. We're hiring.
Look, we've got
we're we're we have six people. We have
our office in Taipei 101.
Five of them Taiwanese nationals.
And we'll probably have 20 25 people by
the end of the year. We'll probably have
a couple hundred in the next three to
five years. So That's you know would
love to speak to great people in Taiwan.
The second thing is
yeah if you're trying to do it yourself,
look read a lot
try to talk to the customer and
understand their problems. Um and then
I'll tell you it's just going to be
really hard and really awful.
There's going to be lots of setbacks.
You're going to get you know yeah. It's
painful.
>> [laughter]
>> So, keep yeah. Yeah.
Get get ready for that. That would be my
other piece of advice. Like if you think
it's easy or it's or going to be fun all
the times, it is not.
>> It is not.
>> [laughter]
>> I think entrepreneur is not.
Yeah. [laughter] Jensen Huang actually
love when he's like look like they're
like what would you do now? He's like I
wouldn't do it. It's awful. [laughter]
It's painful. I still do it. Yeah.
It's I can't imagine yeah doing it
again. So [laughter]
Okay. Uh when when when you look back
like 10 years from now maybe, what do
you want Shield AI to be remembered for?
That's a great question. Um
Look, I want Shield AI uh to be known as
a as a company that the warfighters
trust that
that builds incredible products that
deliver amazing value
that really inspire
the warfighter at the end of the day
too. Like XBAT again small right now,
but this is inspirational. Um and I want
us to have
what I the the challenging part I would
say like I would hope we are remembered
for helping deter conflict, but it's
like when you stop um you know
stop something from happening no one
remember you know no one remembers it,
right? It's not talked about it. Yeah.
It's like look
people you know don't talk about right?
If there was a a small fire in the
building and someone took it out with a
fire extinguisher, they only remember
when it was a big fire, right?
And so it's like no that person stopped
it from becoming a big fire. No one
remembers who that is.
But
you know that's okay. Like at the end of
the day
I just want Shield AI to
yeah be known as a company that helps
protect
service members, civilians and has done
it at scale and is well trusted as a as
a partner. Okay.
Great question. So, Brendan thank you so
much for your time. We are really
looking forward to see Hivemind in
action in Taiwan. Yeah. Hivemind, V-BAT,
and XBAT in Taiwan.
Thanks for bringing them all
Thank you.
>> [music]
>> Hey!
Hey!
>> [music]
>> Hey!
Hey!